Jane Abernathy Papers
Jane Abernathy Papers
1913-1962
Abernathy, Jane R.
2 linear ft.
Ms. Abernathy was a teacher for 20 years in the Burrall Sunday School Bible Class for Young Women, Calvary Baptist Church, Washington, D.C. where her husband, Rev. Dr. William S. Abernathy, was pastor. Died 1965.
Correspondence, printed material and writings on religious subjects.
148793
Biographical History
Jane Abernathy was the wife of a minister who served twenty years in the Calvary Baptist Church, Washington, D.C. She wrote on theological subjects for almost fifty years, using some of her ideas in the Burrall Bible Class for girls. She also served in her husband's place, delivering sermons on those occasions when he was unavailable.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Jane Abernathy Papers are divided into three series. Correspondence is a mixture of personal and business letters, etc. Printed material is a collection of church programs, religious pamphlets, and other material related to Calvary Church. Writings includes Mrs. Abernathy's theological ideas spanning the years 1913-1957 as well as eleven folders of undated material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Religion and Philosophy; Church and clergy; Abernathy, Jane R.; Calvary Baptist Church (Washington D.C.); Baptists -- United States.; Bible -- Study and teaching.; Religious education of girls.; Women, Baptist.; Women teachers.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts (document genre); Teachers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Theodore Abernathy (son).
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Assorted, 1921-1939; undated (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Church programs, 1921-1947; 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper, The Calvary Caller, 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - Notebook, Burrall Bible Class, undated (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets, miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Religious, miscellaneous
    - 4 volumes, undated (Box 1)
    - undated, 8 folders (Box 1)
    - undated, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - 1913-1921, 1926-1947, 13 folders (Box 2)
    - 1950-1957 (Box 3)